I have to plan
everything smoothly
in order
to stop all of this.
Which is actually not that difficult
since they already have
feelings for each other.
how did you know that
window is the room of Mr. Juanito?
In fairness,
his room is clean and tidy.
Who are you?!
Miss! Wait!
Don't you dare look!
Juanito.
Carmelita promised me.
That she will not push through
with the wedding.
And you believed her?
Just don't worry anymore, okay?
I will help you and Helena.
On one condition.
Promise me,
no matter what happens,
you'll survive.
I will make sure
from now on
that no other woman will die
in that lake from now on,
because of love.
Seems like you prepared
for this night, Miss.
Support Admin Watch on
kissasia.cam or kisskh.org
Speak for yourself. You
look much more prepared.
You can put your gifts here.
I will put mine later.
What are you doing here?
I'm here to accompany you for a while.
Most people here
haven't met each other yet.
And some who are lucky might
meet the one destined for them.
If you come out often...
And go meet more people,
I'm sure...
Many would admire you
and would want to be friends.
How can you be sure they'll like me?
Because you are
friendly and easy to talk to.
And who told you we're already friends?
You are already a part of my life.
I suppose our first
meeting wasn't really ideal.
Oh, are you referring to...
That day you saved me when I fainted?
Or when...
You thought I was a thief and
you almost had your dog bite me?
Seems only yesterday.
I thought you were a criminal.
But now, we're friends.
Miss, do you want to change
the memory of when we first met?
Let's pretend we haven't met yet.
And tonight is the first
time we'll see each other.
Crazy. Does he want to
do an acting challenge?
Oh well! Whatever happens, so be it!
Of course, i won't let myself lose.
A most wonderful night...
I'm Juanito Alfonso.
May I know your name?
I'm sure it is as beautiful
as the light of the moon.
What is this?
Am I getting jealous?
This can't be, Carmela!
Erase! Erase!
Maria's party that was prepared by Father
was exactly like this right?
For sure.
Ouch!
Carmelita? Do you feel alright?
It hurts.
Your chest hurts?
No... my tummy.
Let's go home.
Alright, I'll come with you.
Let's go. We'll go ahead.
Miss Carmelita.
Yes?
May I talk to you?
Oh, it's you, Angelito.
What is it?
I just have something
I'd like to ask, Miss.
It won't be long and you'll
become a part of our family.
But that will only happen if your wedding
to my brother will push through.
Do take care always.
Juanito told me truth about that night
I caught you inside his bedroom.
Damn. Why would Juanito tell him? Unfair.
I didn't even tell Maria
and Josefina about our plan.
I know he doesn't want
to marry you as well.
But it's not easy to
bargain with our Father.
And I'm sure Don Alejandro
will get angry once he discovers your plan.
I don't want my brother to get hurt.
Did he say he doesn't wanna marry me?
He didn't really say that.
But he likes Miss Helena.
In fact, if you weren't
caught by our Father together,
He was planning to ask Captain Flores
for Helena's hand in marriage.
Don't worry.
I don't really want to get married.
You're so cute.
You know, if you and
Emily will be seen together,
people will think
you're siblings.
Emily?
Is she the one with you
when you went to our house?
Oh, no. That's Theresita.
Theresita?
What family does she belong to?
- She's our servant.
- Miss.
Doña Soledad might be looking for you.
Good morning.
I'll go ahead.
Of course, sir.
You don't have to call me that.
Miss Carmelita.
Juanito's got wrong timing as always.
His brother's trying to make moves here!
Angelito, will you give me
and Miss Carmelita a little privacy?
Such a shy guy. Just like his brother.
It's nice to think that you
became closer to my
brother in a short span of time.
How are you feeling, by the way?
My head was aching last
night that's why we had to go.
But Sonya told me you
were having stomach pains.
And then my stomach hurt.
I had indigestion that's why
we had to go home.
Don't neglect your health.
Eat properly and sleep early.
It's better to exercise once in a while.
Get out more and soak up the sun.
By the way...
Helena agreed to go out with me.
We're going to the field of roses.
Do you want to come?
Does he want me to be a
third-wheel or a chaperone?
No way!
No, thanks. I have lots
of things to do at home.
Good luck to the two of you.
What did you say?
Good... Good luck?
Oh,
it's an expression
Maria, Josefina and I
say when we want to
encourage someone.
Good luck. Like that.
Good luck.
Dear diary,
I'm supposed to be happy for them.
But what is this?
I can't explain what
I'm feeling now.
I am here to be the bridge
for Juanito and Helena.
Just like how I became a
bridge for James and Shae.
But unlike Shae...
I'm not a traitor.
And I will never fall for Juanito.
Because it's not right to
fall in love with someone
who is already in love with someone else.
Totally confused,
Carmela.
Why did Juanito tell me
that he's going on a date with Helena?
While I'm dying of boredom here.
No... I just drank too much coffee.
Right... That's right..
Carmelita?
Do you want to come and stroll around
the hacienda with Theresita and I?
Wait, is Carmelita like this too?
Stuck inside her room?
I don't want to be like her.
I'm going out.
It's a good thing you decided
to come with us, Carmelita.
Of couse,
I want to get busy so
I wouldn't wonder how
happy Juanito must be
with Helena right now.
Carmelita!
Sonya, what are you doing here?
I heard that Eduardo will
serenade Maria later tonight.
Juanito will play the guitar
and they will be accompanied by Ignacio.
That's why I brought Helena with me.
Won't...
Father and Mother see?
They'll be heading home tomorrow.
So there won't be any problem.
Gosh! She's wearing it.
Thank you very much
for your gift, Carmelita.
You chose really well.
Juanito noticed this hair pin as well.
It suits you.
OMG. Was she wearing that during her date
with Juanito earlier?
It's okay. I'm sure there's
lots of hair clips like that.
Shit. What if Juanito asked her
where she bought that clip?
I feel like I want to faint.
Do I look alright?
- Of course!
- They're here!
♪ There's something I want to tell you. ♪
♪ Miss, I'd like you to fall for me too. ♪
♪ Your smile will stay with me. ♪
♪ Like your gentle heart. ♪
♪ The first time I saw you, I
was stunned by your smile. ♪
♪ My heart was taken,
my life was changed. ♪
♪ There's something I want to tell you. ♪
♪ Miss, I'd like you to fall for me too. ♪
My beloved, Maria.
Please accept my heart.
That beats only for you.
Oh, Juanito.
Since we're already here...
Why don't you sing a song
to Miss Helena as well?
What?
Did I hear that right?
A song to Helena?
Damn! Too many people know about our plan!
Ignacio also knows!
Ignacio, I'm asking you
what you mean by that.
Maria, I'll be the one to explain to you.
Maria...
Thank you for visiting me.
You can all go home now, gentlemen.
Carmelita.
Explain yourself to me.
Maria...
Juanito and I have decided...
To do something to stop the wedding.
Carmelita!
Why did you do that?
You know how important
this is for our family.
What do I do?
I hope she won't tell on me.
I understand that you're still young.
And you're probably
not ready to get married.
But I hope you understand that
this is the will of Father and Mother.
What will they say once
they find out about this?
Don't worry.
Juanito and I will make sure to
say everything at the right time and...
In the proper way.
I'm sorry for not telling you and Josefina.
Carmelita,
I am your sister.
You can tell me anything.
Is there another reason why you did it?
I can't tell her the real reason.
Maria...
I am still in love with Leandro.
I knew it.
You won't easily forget your first love.
Wow,
I didn't know the "I still love
Leandro" excuse would be effective.
You bought too much
again. What are all these?
Father! Mother!
Welcome home!
Good morning, Don Alejandro, Doña Soledad.
Miss Carmelita.
What the hell is he doing here?
How are you and Helena?
All good.
You know, I already told
Maria about our plan last night.
She agreed to it.
That's great.
You know, you did something wrong to me.
That's right.
You told Ignacio and
Angelito about our plan.
It was Sonya who told Ignacio.
And regarding Angelito...
I told him the truth because
he will let our parents know.
that he saw you in my bedroom.
He's right. It's better
for Angelito to know the
truth instead of having
more rumors about us.
To be honest, you were
the one who did me wrong.
Why did you gifted Helena
the hair pin that I gave you?
It's because I forgot
to buy a gift for her.
That's why I ended up gifting it to her.
Besides, wouldn't that make her more happy
since it was you who chose it?
Well, then...
I guess I mean nothing to you.
Juanito!
Hey!
Wait... Juanito!
Annoying!
Why is Juanito like that?
Are you ready, Carmelita?
We're going to Hacienda Alfonso
for Juanito's going-away party.
It's a hard pass for me. He got mad
about a mere hair pin. What a bummer.
Mom I really don't
feel well... It's like...
I'm feeling a bit dizzy.
It's such a shame, then.
He's leaving tomorrow.
but you wouldn't get to see each other.
I am really sorry, Mother.
Alright. You rest here.
Carmelita.
What is that?
A letter from Juanito.
Just put it on the table, Josefina.
Don't you want to read it?
Alright.
You read it first.
Just tell me all about it tomorrow.
Just relax, Carmela, this
doesn't mean anything.
Nothing.
It's because you didn't attend his party
that's why he's gonna ask a favor.
Don't assume anything.
Don't assume anything...
Carmelita,
first of all,
I want to apologize for the way I acted.
I realize that you are not here
because you don't want to see me.
I truly understand.
You might be also aware
that I am coming back to Manila tomorrow.
I regret not being
able to travel with you.
According to Josefina,
you'll be leaving by Friday.
Carmelita,
If your anger towards me has dissipated,
may I talk to you tomorrow?
There's something I want to tell you.
I hope you can come.
I will be waiting.
Juanito.
Oh. What's that, Carmela?
Why are you smiling?
That can't be.
That can't be. No way.
But it's really quite difficult.
Juanito's so irritating.
You're irritating, Juanito!
Josefina, good morning.
Where is Father and Mother?
I will ask for permission.
They're still sleeping.
What do I do about this then?
I'll handle it.
I will tell them you went to the garden
to gather ingredients for breakfast.
Alright.
I'll make myself pretty. I'm excited.
Good morning to you.
Helena...
I'll go ahead so you two can talk.
What are you doing here?
You are the reason
Juanito and I became closer.
I wanted you to be the first to know.
I'm planning on accepting
his proposal today.
I'll go to him now to surprise him.
She's getting ahead of me, huh?
Wait...
She'll accept Juanito's proposal?
Does that mean they'll be a couple?
Carmelita?
I was just stunned.
I'm happy for the two of you.
Yeah.
Thank you so much, Carmelita.
You're such a true friend.
The necklace...
Juanito said
he'll only give that to the
woman who will own his heart.
It's really Helena whom he loves.
I won't see him then.
I don't care if he thinks I'm mad at him.
It's the right thing to do.
So that the plan will be successful.
Then I'll fulfill my mission
and go back to my own time.
But
why do I feel this way?
I should be happy.
But I feel differently...
One week has passed
but I'm still here.
Patiently waiting if Carmelita and
Juanito's destiny will still come true.
And my persistent feelings
are slowly disappearing.
I'm okay now,
I'm not even complaining.
except for...
Miss Carmelita.
A new letter came from Sir Juanito.
Juanito is quite eager in sending letters.
That's the third one this week.
I'll read it later.
Are you not reading it?
I don't want to reply to his letters.
I don't want to ruin his
relationship with Helena.
This other letter is still
addressed to you, Miss.
This is from Miss Natasha.
Natasha?
Why would she write to me?
She wants to teach me how to cook?
That's great.
Natasha is known for
her skills in cooking.
I don't want to go out.
I apologize, Mother.
Thank you.
I noticed you seem edgy since
the day Juanito left for Manila.
You need something to take up your time.
Don't worry, Carmelita.
I'll just accompany you.
We're not gonna be there long.
What's important is that we show up.
I'm glad you accepted my invitation.
Plastic.
Just the other day, she's
arguing with Maria and I,
but now she's acting
like where best friends.
It was our Mother's
wish for us to come here.
Let us go to the kitchen?
I forgot the cook book
we need for this recipe.
Can you get it from
Father's office, Carmelita?
It's just on the table.
Wait a minute...
is she giving me orders?
Shall we go ahead, Maria?
This isn't the cookbook
she's talking about.
As if we're friends.
She's got a screw loose, I think.
Where is it?
This is a dictionary.
It's not here.
- Natasha's so annoying.
- Are you looking for this?
Oh. Yes, it is.
Yes, that right. This is it.
I've only been away for seven months,
but it seems like you've
already forgotten me, Carmelita.
You're handsome, but that doesn't
mean you can just hold my hand like that.
Seems like he knows Carmelita.
It's pretending time again.
How are you doing?
You've changed so much.
Well, I'll be going.
So much to do in the kitchen.
Are you not mad at me anymore?
Why would I be angry at you?
Leandro.
When did you return to San Alfonso?
Oh my gosh!
What am I gonna do?
He's Leandro and he's back?
I was supposed to come back next year.
But the terrible news came to me.
That my love is set to be married.
He's saying too much
and I don't even know him.
Why would Maria leave me in this moment?
I'm sorry.
I forget that you're still mad at me.
So, Carmelita is mad with her ex?
That's alright.
Maybe I just need some
time to think things through.
I didn't think the "I need time and
space" excuse would be effective too.
Do you mean to say...
There's still a chance
you might forgive me?
I don't know?
Maybe?
I'm not sure.
I will do everything for you to forgive me.
My love,
I am hoping we can
rekindle our relationship.
He looks sincere.
But I am not your ex.
Why am I always put
in a stressful situation?
Do you still remember?
Before I left...
I have given you something.
But you didn't accept it.
What? Is he proposing?
I hope you'll accept my love for you.
Even if we don't end up together...
It is still for you.
Is this for real?
It's a real diamond! I wonder
how much I can sell this for.
Do you still remember?
What I told you before I left?
I promised you...
That I shall return.
I understand it wholeheartedly
if you won't be able to wait for me.
But...
I didn't expect it.
That you would agree to get married
to the son of Don Mariano Alfonso.
I was deeply hurt.
But I found hope when
Helena wrote me a letter...
Saying...
you didn't really want
to get married to Juanito.
Because
you still hold me inside your heart.
That's right.
I used Leandro's name
to convince Helena
that I don't like Juanito.
Wrong move.
Helena's quick to divulge it.
That's why I fought hard.
I promised
that I will return to you.
Even though we faced storms in the sea.
I prayed
for a safe return.
So that I may be by your side, Carmelita.
Poor guy...
Maybe Carmelita was mad at him.
But I'm not Carmelita.
There's no reason for me to be mad.
can we meet at the church?
Oh gosh, won't he let me be?
I just want a peaceful life.
If I agree to meet him,
he'll ask too many questions.
But I don't know him!
We're total strangers!
Miss,
you don't plan to meet up with Mr. Leandro?
You read that?
Miss Carmelita,
I understand that you are
still upset with Mr. Leandro.
But I feel that he
completely regrets leaving.
What is this?
I don't even know what
that guy did to Carmelita.
It's better for me to avoid him.
I don't have to right to forgive.
I'm not Carmelita.
I wasn't the one who loved and got hurt.
Carmelita?
You can't sleep as well?
Same for me.
Maybe it's normal when
one thinks of too many things.
Do you have a problem?
For the past ten years,
this problem and worry of mine...
Still lingers up to this day.
You know the first time
I disobeyed Mother.
Now I know who I got
this spunky attitude from.
Since then...
Eduardo and I became close.
And when I became fourteen...
He confessed his love to me.
He secretly courted me for about a year.
That is why...
I am thankful.
That up until now, you and
Josefina kept our relationship secret.
What if you tell Father
and Mother about it?
So you can prepare for your wedding.
I wish it's that simple.
But...
Father and Mother would not allow it.
Eduardo comes from a poor family.
His father, Raul,
is our butcher.
And his mother is sick.
And Theresita
our servant.
That's right.
Status is everything in their era.
I'm afraid that
once Father discovers everything...
He'll take me away from Eduardo.
What if Father understands?
We don't know what he's capable of.
He once said
that he could stand to lose anything
but not the honor and name of our family.
That's why, Carmelita...
I hope you don't throw away
the love you have with Leandro.
I hope you give him a
chance to make it up to you.
And if you and Juanito succeed
in stopping the wedding...
And he and Helena end up with each other...
I hope you open up your heart again...
For Leandro.
Carmelita,
I hope you will give me a chance.
Don't worry.
I will do everything
for us to be together again.
You two seem busy at this moment.
Your family has been invited
to the birthday of the
Governor General in Manila.
I'm sure your Aunt Rosario
will be pleased to see you.
Ladies and gentlemen!
Tonight we celebrate
- not only with good food,
- Salud!
Miss Carmelita.
May I have this dance?
I'm just wondering.
If I'm here now inside
Carmelita's body…
Where is the real Carmelita?
She's here right with you.
You're holding her right now.
OMG.
Is Carmelita inside there?!
Are you just worried
or...
are you starting to have
feelings for her?